Never forget why you are the church.
Romans try to throw right back into it as we continue through this
text that is absolutely filled with truth for every
part of our everyday life.
Romans 12 is a collection of commandments that we, as believers,
are expected to obey.
Listen, God does not give us commandments just for suggestions.
God doesn't give us commandments just for good, interesting reads.
God gives us commandments in his words so we can
obey them and follow them in our life.
Now, I want to remind you in saying that God's
commandments are not to limit or to hinder our enjoyment of life.
Have you ever thought about rules hindering your enjoyment?
Listen, if you ever have kids or if you've raised
kids or maybe you got grandkids, whatever it is, right?
You understand it.
you put rules and you tell your kids, this is what we're going to do, this is what we're not going to do.
And they say, man, that's just not fair, right?
And I'll tell you, River has this thing that she says.
It's the most frustrating, irritating thing ever.
She goes, this is just the worst day.
Now mind you, it changes about 50 times in a day.
This is the best day, daddy.
This is the worst day.
This is the best, but it's contingent on what's going on, but
when we tell her rules, right?
When we say, listen, you got to brush your teeth.
That is not an option.
That's not a suggestion.
Go get the toothbrush and brush your teeth.
Why?
Because if you don't, your teeth will rot out.
That is a protecting commandment, which you understand what I'm saying.
I'm not trying to limit her life.
I'm trying to have her life be more enjoyable.
The commandments that God gives us or
for our prosperity and joy in this life.
We're so scared of that word prosperity.
Why?
Because people have abused it.
You do realize that he is richly and able to abundantly
supply all your needs.
That is not prosperity gospel.
That the God that we serve.
You find me someone who is living according to the flesh and the ways of this world.
I'll show you someone miserable in their spirit.
I don't care what they post on social media.
Let me just tell you something.
Social media is easy.
You know how long they take to capture that little picture right there?
You know how many filters they got to put on there?
You know how many times they change it?
You know how many times it's this or that?
Listen, social media is easy.
I'm not saying it's bad or wrong or whatever, it can be for the glory of God,
but don't be deceived by it.
Living life and sin is anything but easy though.
If you want to complicate your life, live in disobedience to God.
Everything was perfect in the garden of Eden until what?
They disobeyed, then things became much harder
and much more complicated.
Church, these short little commands found in this chapter are not trivial,
but rather pivotal to a thriving life in this world.
So we're going to look at the next portion of scripture here.
I'm going to read you verses 14 through 20.
If you there, say, read.
Bless them which persecutes you, bless and curse not.
Rejoice with them that do rejoice and weep with them that weep.
Be of the same mind one toward another, mine not high things, but
condescend to men of low estate, be not wise in your own conceits.
Recompense to no man, evil for evil, provide
things honest in the sight of all men, if it be possible,
as much as lieth in you, live peaceably with all men.
Dearly beloved.
Avenge not yourselves, but rather give place unto wrath, for it is
written, vengeance is mine.
I will repay, saith the Lord.
Therefore, if thine enemy hunger feed him.
If he thirsts, give him drink, for in doing so, thou
shalt heap coals of fire on his head.
And in verse 21, it's not on the screen.
It says, be not overcome of evil, but overcome evil with good.
We come to another section in a study with within a
study, within a study, within a study.
You know how we do things around here.
But these past several commands have been how we are to
be in relation to others.
Our actions towards others.
This next portion, however, speaks even more specifically on a believer's
reaction to others, whether others
are Christian or not.
So the title for this morning is very simple.
The power in persecution.
Let's pray.
Father, I thank you, Lord, for this morning.
I thank you for your word.
God, I ask you, God, you just speak to us today, God.
Those that have ears to hear, may they hear.
Well, God, I pray that as we are obedient to you, Lord, that you continue God,
to just guide us and direct us.
God, I pray that we acknowledge your faithfulness, your goodness, your mercy, your grace.
God, I pray that we also acknowledge your righteousness and your holiness.
God, I pray that as you are holy, may we be holy.
God, there's someone here who's lost.
God, I pray today you saved them through them confessing with their mouth, that
Jesus is Lord, believe in their heart, that you raise them in a dead.
And God, there's a wayward Christian, a wayward believer,
a saint who has gone and going the wrong way, living in sin.
God, I pray, Lord, 1st off, I pray they're miserable.
But God, I pray, Lord, today, they can come back to you, God.
Since you say, pray.
Amen.
There are too many people who claim to follow Jesus.
But yet in their responses and reactions to others, there is no indication
of Christ-likeness at all.
So let's look at what scripture says about this.
We see the 1st command.
In Romans 12, verse 14, bless
them which persecutes you.
Bless and curse not.
Now, for us to understand what we are responding to, we
have to understand what it means to be persecuted.
That word persecute in the Greek literally means to
pursue and follow in haste.
It gives the idea of an active hostility.
It is when someone is directly attacking you.
Now, if not careful, we can call anything and everything
persecution.
I want you to know something.
And I was telling the students, I think it was Wednesday, that
God does not give us the liberty to redefine
things that he's already defined.
So when we look at persecution, we have to we have to make sure that
we understand what he's saying here, for example, not
everything is a trial and not everything is persecution.
Waking up on the wrong side of the bed is not tribulation.
It may be crankiness, but it's not the fiery trial.
But see, some of us would wake up on the wrong side of the bed and
treat others unkindly and crankily
and say, well, I'm just being persecuted.
I'm just in a tribulation, right?
No, you're not.
You're tired and you're cranky, and that's okay, but admit it.
Acknowledge what it is.
In the same sense, just because someone looks at you sideways and gets sarcastic with you.
That's not persecution.
We become too soft in our feelings to get anything done for God often.
Oh well, I'm not going back to that church.
The preacher didn't shake my hand.
Well, you didn't shake mine.
I mean, I shake hands all the time.
Listen, I try I try my best.
to meet every single person that's new.
I try my best to remember your names.
I try my best to make sure everyone feels loved.
guess what?
I'm going to miss somebody every now and again.
If that's what you're if you're waiting for that
to leave, you can go ahead and leave because it's going to happen.
Y with me this morning.
Some of y'all didn't like that.
I don't know if I like that, but that's what it was said.
Your family not tolerating your reckless and sinful lifestyle.
is not persecution.
Your boss at work sending you an email telling you to get to work on
time is not persecution.
Your church holding you to a standard of holiness is not persecution.
A teacher bringing up your child's wild rebellious behavior is
not persecution.
Just because you don't like how something is going or how something ends up,
that doesn't make you a victim.
Of persecution.
Why am I making this distinction?
Because according to scripture, there is actual persecution that
can arise and will arise in a believer's life.
And if we cannot handle everyday interactions that cause certain
amounts of accountability or pressure,
How are we going to handle actual persecution when it comes?
Now here's what you need to know about biblical persecution.
Biblical persecution is the result only
the result of biblical obedience.
If you're living in sin, You're not getting biblical persecution.
You might get some chastisement for the Lord.
Your heavenly Father might be giving you a whooping.
But you're not you're not getting biblical persecution.
The only reason why this world would persecute you
is because you are living and looking too much like Christ.
And the world hates Jesus.
In scripture, we see several examples of persecution, a person perspective,
how we ought to view it.
Really the intensity of it.
This really opens our minds to the fact that some of
these little petty things that we complain about so often is not is nothing
but just simple little things that we can just move on from.
What were the qual- we look here and we see a man named Stephen?
We are introduced to Stephen in Acts chapter 6.
He is one of the 7 men selected to be the 1st deacons of the early church.
All 7 men are named, but there's more description given
to Stephen.
What were the qualifications of these men.
Well, Acts chapter 6, verse one and 3 says this.
Now at this time, while the disciples were increasing in number,
a complaint arose on the part of the Hellenistic
Jews against the native Hebrews, because their widows
were being overlooked in the daily serving of food.
By the way, I want you to know that complaining and griping
out predates the church by a whole lot.
People say, well, you know, everyone's complaining.
just how we do things.
Listen, just because someone else wants to sin doesn't mean I want to.
Okay.
So the 12 summoned a congregation of disciples and said, it is not desirable
for us to neglect the word of God in order to serve tables.
Therefore, brethren, select from among you 7
men of good reputation, full of spirit and of wisdom, whom
we may put in charge of this task.
And so they did it.
And one of them was named Stephen.
We see in verse 5 in a saying, please the whole multitude, and they chose Stephen,
a man full of faith and of the Holy Ghost.
And Philip and Philip, I didn't know you were that old, dog.
That's pretty old right there.
And Prochorus and Nicanor and Timon and
Parmenist and Nicholas a proselyte of Antioch.
Now we see that Stephen was busy and on mission.
It says in verse 8, and Stephen, full of faith and power, the great
wonders and miracles among the people.
So let's just get this straight right here before we go any further.
Stephen, obviously a man of wisdom full of the Holy Spirit.
He was already doing things that a disciples should do.
He was already serving.
He was already teaching.
He was already preaching.
He was already doing all things.
He didn't need anything special to happen.
Now he just has another assignment.
But we see him out and he's preaching.
He's doing great wonders and miracles among the people.
And you're thinking, man, everyone love him.
That's not how it turned out in scripture.
Look at this.
This actually caused anger with some of the opposers of Christ.
Look at verses 9 through 15 of Act 6.
We're going to be reading a lot of scripture today so just get ready for it.
But some men from what was called the synagogue of the freedmen,
including both Cyrenians and Alexandrians, and some
from Cilicia and Asia, rose up and argued with Stephen.
But they were unable to cope with the wisdom and the spirit, which
was with which he was speaking.
Then they secretly induced men to say we have heard him speak blasphemous
words against Moses and against God.
And they stirred up the people.
The elders and the scribes and they came up to him and dragged him away and
brought him before the council.
They put forth false witnesses who said, this man incentively
speaks against the holy place and the law, for we have heard him
say that this Nazarene Jesus would destroy
this place and altar, the customs which Moses
handed down to us, and fixing their gaze on him, all who
were sitting in the council, saw his face like the face of an angel.
Church Stephen.
was facing persecution.
There was an active and direct attack on this man because
of his faith and boldness for Christ.
I need you to understand something, by the way.
If you find yourself stirring up.
In the church.
I want you I want you to read the book of Acts.
Every single time.
Every single time that you see,
And they were stirring up.
It was the enemies of Christ, stirring up the people,
to oppose the people of God.
As a matter of fact, the only time that we see
Now you may find one time or here or there, whatever, but Paul
was accused of stirring up.
But it was a false accusation.
What I'm trying to say is this, listen, if you find yourself in situations
where you're constantly complaining, constantly stirring up, constantly doing this,
constantly doing that, understand you're not on the right side of things.
You say, well, I'm right.
Okay, well, there's a there's a way to be right and a way to be wrong.
Are y'all with me?
So church Stephen is being persecuted.
This is not where it ends, though.
See, persecution, like we are talking about here, does not end all of a sudden.
I mean, these men have stirred up the crowd.
They have put forth false witnesses.
They have dragged him up before the council.
This is not just a debate in the hallway.
This is not just an argument in the parking lot.
This is we want you dead.
We're sick and tired of you speaking.
We try to question you.
You were too wise and you were told the Holy Spirit, so we
couldn't get you, now you made us matter.
We're going to try to kill you.
Okay, well, the high priest questions him about the accusations in Acts 7, verse one.
Then said the high priest, are these things so?
And Stephen responds, by the way, you know that when you're living in truth, you don't have to really defend yourself.
Let the haters hate is what they say these days.
Amen?
But Stephen responds, Acts chapter 2, 7, verse 2.
And he said, hear me, brethren, and fathers.
He proceeds to not answer their question.
He proceeds to preach a message starting with Abraham
all the way to Jesus, the Messiah.
He then points to the council as guilty of the blood of Jesus.
Now, understand what just happened.
He's already been falsely accused.
He's already been dragged to the council.
He's already he's in the midst of persecution.
But yet in bonus, he says, you're guilty.
How does he say it?
Well, Acts chapter 7, verse 51 through 53.
You men who are stiff necked and
uncircumcised in heart and ears are always resisting the Holy Spirit.
You are doing just as your fathers did.
Which one of the prophets did your fathers not persecute?
They killed those who had previously announced the coming of the righteous one.
whose betrayers and murderers you have now become.
You will receive the law as ordained by angels, or you
who receive the law as ordained by angels, and yet did not
keep it.
Now hear me out.
I wonder why the apostles told the disciples to pick men who are
full of faith and wisdom in the Holy Spirit.
Because I'm going to tell you right now, if you're in a situation Stephen
was in and you are not full of faith in the Holy Spirit, you will not respond like he did.
That was the Holy Spirit talking.
By the way, when he speaks to their fathers who persecuted the prophets, the
same word for persecuted is used here as in Romans 12.
An active and direct attack.
Well, we know this didn't go over too well.
These men were more stiff-necked than what Stephen even said.
And so what happened?
We'll look at verse 54 through 59 of Act 7.
Now when they heard this, they were cut to the quick, and they began gnashing their teeth at him.
But being full of the Holy Spirit,
Do you realize how important the Holy Spirit is?
I mean, over and over again, full the Holy Spirit, full the Holy Spirit, full the Holy Spirit.
He gazed intently into heaven and saw the glory of God.
And Jesus standing at the right hand of God.
What a sight that would be.
And he said, behold, I see the heavens opened up and the Son of Man
standing at the right hand of God, but they cried out with a loud voice and
covered their ears and rushed at him with one impulse.
When they had driven him out of the city, they began stoning him.
And the witnesses laid aside their robes at the feet of a young man named Saul.
They went on stoning Stephen as he called on the Lord and said, Lord Jesus, receive my spirit.
That makes our quote unquote persecutions look pretty silly, does it not?
Church Stephen endured persecution, but this is just part of the text here
in Romans 12, verse 14.
Remember, blessed them which persecutes you, blessed and curse not.
Look at the last words of this man in verse 60 of Acts
7, then falling on his knees.
He cried out with a loud voice, Lord, do not hold this sin against them.
Having said this, he fell asleep.
Here's another reason why you have to be full of the Holy Spirit because I'm going to tell you right now.
If you're not full of the Holy Spirit, And people start throwing rocks
at you, and stones at you, and the
intention to kill you, Is that how you'd respond?
See, most of us, and again, I know that I know this is this is hard to put ourselves into.
Like, I don't want to be stoned.
I want any of you be stoned.
But I just have a feeling that I'd probably pick up a rock and throw it back.
But again, when you are this right with God.
When you are this on, notice while it's happening, his gaze
was intent on the heavens.
Lord did not hold us against him.
Remember, bless and do not curse.
If this doesn't reverberate throughout your heart and spirit, then may I remind you
of another example of this.
His name's Jesus.
Jesus, what you're saying about him, Jesus of Nazareth, the son of a carpenter,
the son of Mary, known by his hometown, the son of man, the son of God.
He too went about and before miracles and wonders.
He too preached to the masses, the everlasting truth.
Now you say, well, what's the difference between Jesus and Stephen?
Well, Stephen was full of the Holy Ghost.
Jesus is God.
Stephen taught the word, Jesus is the word.
Stephen died for the sake of Christ.
Jesus died for the sins of the world.
Jesus was falsely accused, beaten up for no cause.
Drug to the council, brought before judges,
given over to a Roman crucifixion at the hands of wicked men.
He was flogged.
He was mocked, he was spit on, humiliated, hung on a tree in
front of all the sea, nails driven brutally through his hands and feet,
a crown of thorns pushed upon his brow.
He was so inflicted physically, you could barely recognize
him as a human being.
for a description of this right out of scripture in Isaiah 53.
But he was wounded for our transgressions, he was bruised for our iniquities.
The chastisement of our peace was upon him, and with his stripes, we are healed.
All we, like sheep, have gone astray.
We have turned every one to his own way, and the Lord hath laid on him the
iniquity of us all.
He was oppressed.
He was afflicted, yet he opened not his mouth.
He's brought us a lamb to the slaughter.
And as a sheep before her shearer is
dumb, so he openeth not his mouth.
He was taken from prison and from judgment, and
who shall declare his generation, for he was cut off out of the land of
the living, for the transgression of my people was
he stricken.
This is persecution.
Yet how did he respond?
Remember, Jesus had the authority to stop all of this.
Matthew 26, 53, or do you think that I cannot appeal to
my father and he will at once put at my disposal
more than 12 legions of angels?
He had the authority to stop it.
But he did not.
His persecution was necessary for the forgiveness of our sins.
But what did Jesus say on Luke 23.
In verse 33, when they came to a place called the Skull.
There they crucified him and the criminals, one on
the right and the other on the left.
But Jesus was saying, Father, forgive them.
For they do not know what they are doing.
And they cast laws dividing up his garments among themselves.
I want you to know something.
Jesus was not powerless.
He was meek.
For example, of Jesus, the example of Jesus, Stephen
modeled the biblical response to persecution even to the
death by praying for God's forgiveness of their persecutors.
Think about it for a second.
In the midst of losing their life for Christ.
They blessed.
And they did not curse.
This brings the question, what does it mean to bless?
Well, that word bless here in Romans 1214
literally means to bless, right?
To speak well of, to praise.
Typically refers to speech that pronounces or
is intended to result in positive circumstances for
another person or thing.
Now, you say, well, who in the world am I supposed to?
Talk like that too, bless them which persecute you.
Active attack.
Those who are pursuing you for not your good, but for your detriment.
Speak well of.
Praise.
I'm not saying you praise their actions.
I'm saying you bless them.
Remember the statement I made at the beginning of this message?
Let me repeat it.
There are too many people who claim to follow Jesus, but yet in their responses and
reactions to others, there is no indication of Christ-likeness at all.
Where do we see this in our society?
How about the ways that we gossip about those that we don't like or have done us wrong?
Well, let me just tell you what this person did.
Well, let me listen, hey, if you're thinking that I'm standing up
here completely innocent of all these things, I
fall in these and being guilty of this as well.
And that's why it hurts.
It's easy to curse.
It's very difficult to bless.
It's easy to talk bad about someone who did you wrong.
It's very difficult to bless that same person.
It's easy to go around slandering and gossiping.
It's very difficult.
to speak well of.
The way that the moment we get in a conversation or encounter with certain people,
we instantly get tense and irate.
Listen, I've seen it in leadership and me being
as a leader and I get to people and for some reason, it's like the
moment you start talking, it's they get tense and it's almost like you can see
the bitterness and the anger coming out of them.
Some of us don't realize just how downright disrespectful
we are to people that we don't agree with.
with those that do things a certain way differently than us.
I've heard it in our very own hallways.
Someone doesn't live to an expectation, someone doesn't live to a standard,
someone doesn't live to this, live to that.
And all of a sudden we think that gives us a right to curse them.
Oh, I'm not cursing them.
No, no, no.
Yes, you are.
Don't even get me started on social media.
I'm exhausted by people who claim to know Christ post in such a way that is
the disgusting display of cursing rather than blessing.
Well, preacher the truth is the truth.
Can I tell you something?
You can say the right thing the wrong way and ruin the message.
God's word does not does not shy away from hard topics.
But God's word handles them perfectly.
In other words, once we get out of God's word, and we start throwing
all this personal agenda and personal,
this face towards others,
We've gone outside of the parameters that God has set for us.
We are cursing.
And not blessing.
Most of us default to the cursing.
Well, and you say, okay, well, what does it mean to curse?
Well, that word curse literally means to curse, pronounce a
curse upon, refers to the act of pronouncing
misfortune for someone else.
Now you say, well, that sounds a little bit insane and crazy.
If we don't say it out loud,
How often is that where our heart is set towards others?
How often is in our reactions, in our facial
expressions, in the eye rolls, and the
turn the back toes, how often do we curse
with the way we interact?
I want us to notice something about this command.
Look again, Romans 12, 14, blessed them which persecutes you, blessing, curse not.
If you were me saying, amen.
The them here does not just refer to saved people.
This commandment speaks in our encounters with both the lost and the
saved, but if we can't even bless the brethren,
If we can't bless our brothers and sisters in Christ,
how in the world are we going to bless those who are lost?
I want you to know something.
Just about everyone that's here is here for the same reason.
We're here to worship the Lord.
We're here to learn from God's Word.
We're here to fellowship with the saints.
When persecution comes, no matter who it comes from, we have to understand the
power and persecution.
We need to see it as scripture reveals it.
Now, remember, I'm talking to you about things that we interact with.
We interact and we curse more than we bless.
And it's because it's easier than it is to bless somebody.
And by the way, I'm not saying this.
I'm not saying you go around and you be that superficial little fake person.
It's blessing somebody to their face and cursing them behind their back.
That's hypocrisy.
That's lying.
That's deception.
And listen, that's easy to do too.
You know, most sin is easy.
Most sin is easy for us to commit.
But we need to see persecution as scripture reveals it.
Jesus teaches in a sermon on the Mount.
Matthew 5, verse 10 through 12.
Blessed are those who have been persecuted for the sake of righteousness, for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.
Blessed are you when people insult you and persecute you and
falsely see all kinds of people with things against you because of me.
Rejoice and be glad for your reward is in heaven is great.
For in the same way they persecuted the prophets who were before you.
Noticed on verse 11, and falsely say all kinds
of evil against you because of me.
That's not just because of how you have a bad attitude or how you did someone wrong.
No, it's for the sake of Christ, it's because you follow Jesus.
Matthew 544 through 48, but I say to you, love
your enemies and pray for those who persecute you.
So that you may be sons of your father who is in heaven,
for he causes his son to rise in the evil and the good and sends
rain on the righteous and the unrighteous.
Matthew 5, 44 through 48,
For if you love those who love you, what reward do you have?
You know what that means?
Oh, well, you know, I love him.
I just don't want be in the same room with them.
Try that with your wife.
Try that with your spouse.
How's that going to go?
Hey, baby, I'm out in the living room, watching my TV.
I love you.
I just really don't want to be with you right now.
Excuse my language, kiddos.
You see how stupid that sounds?
But yeah, we do it all the time.
Oh, I just, I love them and man, I'm excited to
go to heaven for all eternity with them.
I hope their mansions beside me.
They just I just don't want to sit beside them at church this morning.
I can't serve with them.
I just, we don't get alone.
Well,
If you love those who love you, what reward do you have?
Do not even the tax collectors do the same.
If you greet only your brothers, what more are you doing than others?
Do not even the Gentiles do the same, therefore, you are to be perfect
as your heavenly Father is perfect.
You know what I found?
People outside the church are more respectful to each
other than those inside the church.
God forbid that be here.
Luke 628, bless those who curse you and pray for those who mistreat you.
Well, pastor, I don't want to.
It doesn't matter.
That's what we're told do.
Sometimes if we would just look at the Bible in obedience, and
it takes the decision away from us, it actually becomes easier to obey.
But see, sometimes we read the Bible, we think we have an option so we take the option.
Paul told him his status in ministry.
This is Paul, the apostle Paul.
Greatest missionary who's ever walked the earth outside of Jesus Christ himself.
First Corinthians 4, 11 through 16, to this present hour, we are both hungry
and thirsty and are poorly clothed and are roughly treated and are homeless.
And we toil working with our hands.
When we are revolved, we bless, when we are persecuted, we endure,
when we are slandered, we try to conciliate.
We have become the scum of the world.
The dregs of all things, even until now.
I do not write these things to shame you, but to
admonish you as my beloved children.
For if you were to have countless tutors in Christ, yet
you would not have many fathers, for in Christ Jesus, I became your
father through the gospel.
Therefore, I exhort you, be imitators of me.
What Paul is saying is, even through all the persecution and all
the mistreatment, there is a purpose, this power in the persecution.
We are not to see this as the world sees it.
There is no biblical get back at them doctrine.
There's never a justification for gossip and slandering someone who has done you wrong.
And I get I've been guilty of all these things.
I've already told you that, but no matter what people have done to me and said about me,
I stand here before you, it breath in my lungs and a calling on my life.
They can't take that away.
Well, they might be able to take away the breath of my lungs.
That's why I got Buddy right here in Carlos and everyone, you know, if you try, they're going to tackle you.
Amen.
Okay.
But listen, I'm commanded to live above the filthy standard of the world.
And I can tell you this, we may have some You may have
had some bad things happening to you.
But you haven't been stoned to death.
You haven't been put on our
on our Roman cross and crucified.
You say, oh, that's just trivial.
No, these things happened.
As far as I can tell, you've got your head on your shoulders attached.
Listen, people are getting their head cut off.
We're not being persecuted, church.
Why not?
If there's power and persecution.
Why are we not being persecuted?
You say, preacher, you want to be persecuted?
No, that's not what I'm saying.
I'm just asking very simply, why is it not happening?
Why would they?
May we be obedient to the word, bless them which persecutes you, bless, and curse not.
This morning, I just wonder where this hits you.
Maybe you're someone who just loves to curse people.
Loves to speak ill.
And you do it in the name, it's, you know, it's like that old joke.
We love the gospel through a prayer request.
Hey, pray for so-and-so.
This is what happened to them.
We love we love to act like we're doing our responsibilities by
by pushing somebody down or
It matters how we respond to others.
So this morning, if you if someone had to categorize you in
2 in only 2 ways.
Are you someone who blesses?
Well, you someone who curses.
But hezbound eyes closed all over his place.